<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Home</title>
    <link>https://sarabert96.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 01:54:03 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sarabert96.github.io/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://sarabert96.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 21:05:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarabert96.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact me</title>
      <link>https://sarabert96.github.io/contactme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 01:54:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarabert96.github.io/contactme/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank you</title>
      <link>https://sarabert96.github.io/thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 01:54:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarabert96.github.io/thanks/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://sarabert96.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 01:06:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarabert96.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;short-version&#34;&gt;Short version&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a degree in IT and a Bachelor in languages, I am currently focusing on computational linguistics in a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree. For this reason, my skills are both practical and theoretical, namely programming, speaking foreign languages and use technology in everyday life. I also enjoy photography and therefore I learned by myself the basics of photo editing and I practice juggling in my spare time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;long-version&#34;&gt;Long version&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was born on 7th February 1996 in Northern Italy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing up I developed an interest in technologies and languages, therefore during high school I chose the Information Technology career at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itiszuccante.edu.it/&#34;&gt;C. Zuccante institute&lt;/a&gt;, getting the diploma in 2015. After that, I decided to persue the passion for languages enrolling at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unive.it/&#34;&gt;Ca&amp;rsquo; Foscari University of Venice&lt;/a&gt; to study Portuguese and Spanish, obtaining the degree in 2018. During my Bachelor I discovered the field of Linguistics, and I got extremely fascinated by that: I had no idea there was a scientific method to study languages, actually, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that there was science behind languages at all! But suddently, things got even better: thanks to some friends&amp;rsquo; advices the area of computational linguistics came up, offering the chance to combine my previous knowledge and interest for technologies with my new discovery. So I decided to enroll at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unipi.it/&#34;&gt;University of Pisa&lt;/a&gt; to study a &lt;a href=&#34;https://infouma.fileli.unipi.it/&#34;&gt;Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Digital Humanities&lt;/a&gt; where I specialized in computational linguistics doing exams such as Machine Learning, Human Language Technologies, Data Mining, Applied Linguistics.
I&amp;rsquo;m currently finishing the Master doing a traineeship and a thesis project in collaboration with the COLT group of University of Barcelona.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can use the PC to pursue my daily necessities, but I won&amp;rsquo;t lie, most of the time the only thing I do is search for youtube tutorial regarding what I need! But, then again, that&amp;rsquo;s the perk of living in the Digital Age: the possibility to learn stuff by ourselves and help each other&amp;hellip;I believe if somebody before me was able to do something, I can do it too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beside that, I am also a juggler in my &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t know what to do&amp;rdquo; moments and I like photography, but I never studied in detail these two things. Maybe, one day&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
